<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Avil Page (getting good at life)</title><link>http://www.avilpage.com</link><description></description><atom:link rel="self" href="http://www.avilpage.com/categories/getting-good-at-life.xml" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2016 13:28:49 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>https://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Living A Life Without Goals!</title><link>http://www.avilpage.com/2014/01/living-life-without-goals/</link><dc:creator>Chillar Anand</dc:creator><description>&lt;div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"&gt;&lt;div class="entry" style="background-color: white; color: #333333; line-height: 30px;"&gt;&lt;blockquote style="border-left-color: rgb(165, 171, 171); border-left-style: solid; border-left-width: 1px; margin: 0px; padding: 0px 12px;"&gt;&lt;div style="margin: 30px auto;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: inherit;"&gt;“By letting it go it all gets done. The world is won by those who let it go. But when you try and try. The world is beyond the winning.” &lt;strong style="color: #555555;"&gt;- Lao Tzu&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;div style="margin: 30px auto;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: inherit;"&gt;One of the unshakable tenets of success and productivity literature is that you need to have goals in order to be successful (see &lt;a href="http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2009/09/the-hierarchy-of-success.html" style="border-color: rgb(192, 192, 192); border-style: none none solid; border-width: 0px 0px 1px; color: #303030; text-decoration: none;"&gt;Seth Godin&lt;/a&gt; on this – he’s someone I respect, btw).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="margin: 30px auto;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: inherit;"&gt;And from this tenet comes all sorts of other beliefs:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;ul style="padding: 0.5em 0em 1em 3.2em;"&gt;&lt;li style="padding: 6px 0px 0px;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: inherit;"&gt;You need to set goals the right way (such as the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SMART&lt;/span&gt;method).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li style="padding: 6px 0px 0px;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: inherit;"&gt;You need to break goals down into actionable tasks.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li style="padding: 6px 0px 0px;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: inherit;"&gt;You need to have deadlines and timeframes.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li style="padding: 6px 0px 0px;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: inherit;"&gt;You need to make goals the focus of your day.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div style="margin: 30px auto;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: inherit;"&gt;I know this, because I’ve believed it and lived it and written about it, for a long time.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="margin: 30px auto;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: inherit;"&gt;Until recently.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="margin: 30px auto;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: inherit;"&gt;Until recently, I’d always set goals for myself — short-term and long-term ones, with action lists. I’ve made progress on each one, and accomplished a lot of goals. And from this traditional viewpoint, I’ve been successful. So no argument there: goals work, and you can be successful using goals.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="margin: 30px auto;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: inherit;"&gt;But are they the only way?&lt;br&gt;&lt;span id="more-322"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;More recently I’ve moved away from goals, broken free of the shackles of goals. I’ve liberated myself because goals are not ideal, in my way of thinking:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;ul style="padding: 0.5em 0em 1em 3.2em;"&gt;&lt;li style="padding: 6px 0px 0px;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: inherit;"&gt;They are artificial — you aren’t working because you love it, you’re working because you’ve set goals.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li style="padding: 6px 0px 0px;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: inherit;"&gt;They’re constraining — what if you want to work on something not in line with your goals? Shouldn’t we have that freedom?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li style="padding: 6px 0px 0px;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: inherit;"&gt;They put pressure on us to achieve, to get certain things done. Pressure is stressful, and not always in a good way.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li style="padding: 6px 0px 0px;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: inherit;"&gt;When we fail (and we always do), it’s discouraging.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li style="padding: 6px 0px 0px;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: inherit;"&gt;We’re always thinking about the future (goals) instead of the present. I prefer to live in the present.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div style="margin: 30px auto;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: inherit;"&gt;But most of all, here’s the thing with goals: you’re never satisfied. Goals are a way of saying, “When I’ve accomplished this goal (or all these goals), I will be happy then. I’m not happy now, because I haven’t achieved my goals.” This is never said out loud, but it’s what goals really mean. The problem is, when we achieve the goals, we don’t achieve happiness. We set new goals, strive for something new.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="margin: 30px auto;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: inherit;"&gt;And while many people will say that striving for something new is a good thing, that we should always be striving, unfortunately it means we’re never satisfied. We never find contentment. I think that’s sad — we should learn how to be content now, with what we have. It’s what minimalism is all about, really.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="margin: 30px auto;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: inherit;"&gt;And if minimalism is being happy now, with enough, with the present, then how are goals consistent with this? It’s something I’ve tried to reconcile over the last few years, with limited success.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="margin: 30px auto;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: inherit;"&gt;So what would a true minimalist do instead? If we are content now, and we abandon goals, does that mean we do nothing? Sit around or sleep all day?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="margin: 30px auto;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: inherit;"&gt;Not at all. I certainly don’t do that. We should do what makes us happy, follow our passions, do things that make us excited. For me and many people, that’s creating, building new things, expressing ourselves, making something useful or new or beautiful or inspiring.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="margin: 30px auto;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: inherit;"&gt;So here’s what I do, instead of setting and achieving goals:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="margin: 30px auto;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: inherit;"&gt;I do what excites me. Each day. I wake up, and work on things that I’m passionate about, create things that I love creating.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="margin: 30px auto;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: inherit;"&gt;I don’t worry about where I’ll be (professionally) in a year or even six months, but where I am right now.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="margin: 30px auto;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: inherit;"&gt;I don’t make plans, because they’re an illusion — you never know what will happen in a year or even six months. You can try to control what happens, but you’ll lose. Things always come up, sometimes good and sometimes bad, that will disrupt plans. Instead, I’ve learned to go with the flow, to not worry about things that disrupt plans but worry about what to do right now. This allows me to take advantage of opportunities to come up that I could never have planned for, to work on things I couldn’t have known about, to make decisions about what’s best right now, not what I planned a few months ago.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="margin: 30px auto;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: inherit;"&gt;I don’t force things, but do what comes naturally.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="margin: 30px auto;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: inherit;"&gt;And I focus on the present, on being happy now.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="margin: 30px auto;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: inherit;"&gt;This has taken me time — letting go of goals is a scary and uncomfortable thing, but if you let them go gradually, it’s not that hard. I’ve slowly adapted the way I work, and learned to work in the moment, and go with the flow of the world that surrounds me (online and off).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="margin: 30px auto;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: inherit;"&gt;It’s a beautiful way of working. And not incidentally, I’ve accomplished even more this way, without making that a goal. It’s a natural byproduct of doing what you love.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;blockquote style="border-left-color: rgb(165, 171, 171); border-left-style: solid; border-left-width: 1px; margin: 0px; padding: 0px 12px;"&gt;&lt;div style="margin: 30px auto;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: inherit;"&gt;“A good traveler has no fixed plans, and is not intent on arriving.” &lt;strong style="color: #555555;"&gt;- Lao Tzu&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: inherit;"&gt;Credit: &lt;a href="http://www.theminimalists.com/no-goals/" target="_blank"&gt;Leo Babauta, mnmlist.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>anand reddy pandikunta</category><category>articles about life</category><category>getting good at life</category><category>life tips</category><category>life with no goals</category><category>life without goals</category><category>living without goals</category><category>minimalism</category><category>minimalist</category><category>no goals</category><category>personal blog of anand</category><category>self help</category><guid>http://www.avilpage.com/2014/01/living-life-without-goals/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2014 03:34:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>