<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Avil Page (Posts about great zen stories)</title><link>http://www.avilpage.com</link><description></description><atom:link rel="self" href="http://www.avilpage.com/categories/great-zen-stories.xml" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2017 14:18:54 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>[Zen Story] Obedience!</title><link>http://www.avilpage.com/2014/11/zen-story-obedience.html</link><dc:creator>Chillar Anand</dc:creator><description>&lt;div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"&gt;The master Bankei's talks were attended not only by Zen students but by persons of all ranks and sects. He never quoted sutras nor indulged in scholastic dissertations. Instead, his words were spoken directly from his heart to the hearts of his listeners.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;His large audiences angered a priest of the Nichiren sect because the adherents had left to hear about Zen. The self-centered Nichiren priest came to the temple, determined to debate with Bankei.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;"Hey, Zen teacher!" he called out. "Wait a minute. Whoever respects you will obey what you say, but a man like myself does not respect you. Can you make me obey you?"&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;"Come up beside me and I will show you," said Bankei.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Proudly the priest pushed his way through the crowd to the teacher.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Bankei smiled. "Come over to my left side."&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The priest obeyed.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;"No," said Bankei, "we may talk better if you are on the right side. Step over here."&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The priest proudly stepped over to the right&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;"You see," observed Bankei, "you are obeying me and I think you are a very gentle person. Now sit down and listen."&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;========================================================================&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.avilpage.com/search/label/zen"&gt;More Zen Stories&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>amazing zen stories</category><category>best short stories</category><category>best zen stories</category><category>great zen stories</category><category>short stories</category><category>short zen stories</category><category>zen</category><category>zen stories</category><guid>http://www.avilpage.com/2014/11/zen-story-obedience.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2014 18:17:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Zen Story: Laughing Buddha!</title><link>http://www.avilpage.com/2014/11/zen-story-laughing-buddha.html</link><dc:creator>Chillar Anand</dc:creator><description>&lt;div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"&gt;Anyone walking about Chinatowns in America will observe statues of a stout fellow carrying a linen sack. Chinese merchants call him Happy Chinaman or Laughing Buddha.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;This Hotei lived in the T’ang dynasty. He had no desire to call himself a Zen master or to gather many disciples around him. Instead he walked the streets with a big sack into which he would put gifts of candy, fruit, or doughnuts. These he would give to children who gathered around him in play. He established a kindergarten of the streets.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Whenever he met a Zen devotee he would extend his hand and say: “Give me one penny.”&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Once as he was about to play-work another Zen master happened along and inquired: “What is the significance of Zen?”&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Hotei immediately plopped his sack down on the ground in silent answer.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;“Then,” asked the other, “what is the actualization of Zen?”&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;At once the Happy Chinaman swung the sack over his shoulder and continued on his way.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Source: &lt;a href="http://www.101zenstories.org/happy-chinaman/" target="_blank"&gt;101 Zen Stories&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>great zen stories</category><category>short zen stories</category><category>zen</category><category>zen stories</category><guid>http://www.avilpage.com/2014/11/zen-story-laughing-buddha.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2014 20:49:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Mysterious Wall - Best Zen Story By Osho!</title><link>http://www.avilpage.com/2014/05/the-mysterious-wall-best-zen-story-by-osho.html</link><dc:creator>Chillar Anand</dc:creator><description>&lt;div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: inherit;"&gt;Osho is a great story teller. Whether he is writing a book, preaching his students, giving speeches, he tells interesting short stories. I have read a lot of them from his books. This is one of my favorite stories.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: inherit;"&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: inherit;"&gt;Osho I used present tense above because Osho believes that he is '&lt;/span&gt;&lt;quote&gt;Never Born, Never Died. Only Visited this Planet Earth.'&lt;/quote&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: inherit;"&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: inherit;"&gt;The Mysterious Wall!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: inherit;"&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: inherit;"&gt;There was an ancient mysterious wall which stood at the edge of a village, and whenever anyone climbed the wall to look onto the other side, instead of coming back he or she smiled and would jump to the other side, never to return. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: inherit;"&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: inherit;"&gt;The inhabitants of the village became curious as to what could draw these people to the other side of the wall. After all, their village had all the necessities of living a comfortable life.They made an arrangement to where they would tie a person's feet, so that when he or she looked over and wished to jump, they could be pulled back.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: inherit;"&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: inherit;"&gt;The next time someone tried to climb the wall to see what was on the other side, they chained her feet so that she could not go over. She looked on the other side and was delighted at what she saw, and smiled.Those standing below grew curious to question her and pulled her back, but to their great disappointment she had lost the power of speech.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: inherit;"&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: inherit;"&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: inherit;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;"Those who have Seen cannot say. That which has been Seen cannot be painted, cannot bereduced to words. But still each one has to give a try - and the world goes on becoming more and more beautiful because of these efforts."&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>amazing zen stories</category><category>best short zen stories</category><category>great zen stories</category><category>indian short stories</category><category>indian zen stories</category><category>must read zen stories</category><category>osho quotes</category><category>osho short stories</category><category>osho zen stories</category><category>zen</category><guid>http://www.avilpage.com/2014/05/the-mysterious-wall-best-zen-story-by-osho.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2014 03:13:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>