<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Avil Page (peter norvig google)</title><link>http://www.avilpage.com</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://www.avilpage.com/categories/peter-norvig-google.xml" type="application/rss+xml" rel="self"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2016 16:05:16 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>https://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Teach Yourself Programming in Ten Years!</title><link>http://www.avilpage.com/2014/01/avil-page-17-teach-yourself-programming.html</link><dc:creator>Chillar Anand</dc:creator><description>&lt;div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: inherit;"&gt;&lt;span style="background-color: white;"&gt;Walk into any bookstore, and you'll see how to &lt;/span&gt;&lt;i style="background-color: white;"&gt;Teach Yourself Java in 7 Days&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span style="background-color: white;"&gt; alongside endless variations offering to teach Visual Basic, Windows, the Internet, and so on in a few days or hours. I did the following &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/tg/browse/-/468558/104-5938873-6579160" style="background-color: white;"&gt;power search&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="background-color: white;"&gt; at &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/" style="background-color: white;"&gt;Amazon.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="background-color: white;"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;pre style="background-color: white;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: inherit;"&gt;     &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/search-handle-url/ix=books&amp;amp;rank=%2Bfeaturedrank&amp;amp;fqp=power%01pubdate%3A%20after%201992%20and%20title%3A%20days%20and%0D%20%28title%3A%20learn%20or%20title%3A%20teach%20yourself%29&amp;amp;sz=25&amp;amp;pg=1/ref=s_b_np"&gt;pubdate: after 1992 and title: days and&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;      &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/search-handle-url/ix=books&amp;amp;rank=%2Bfeaturedrank&amp;amp;fqp=power%01pubdate%3A%20after%201992%20and%20title%3A%20days%20and%0D%20%28title%3A%20learn%20or%20title%3A%20teach%20yourself%29&amp;amp;sz=25&amp;amp;pg=1/ref=s_b_np"&gt;(title: learn or title: teach yourself)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: inherit;"&gt;&lt;span style="background-color: white;"&gt;and got back 248 hits. The first 78 were computer books (number 79 was &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/0781802245/" style="background-color: white;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;Learn Bengali in 30 days&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="background-color: white;"&gt;). I replaced "days" with &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/search-handle-url/ix=books&amp;amp;rank=%2Bfeaturedrank&amp;amp;fqp=power%01pubdate%3A%20after%201992%20and%20title%3A%20hours%20and%0D%20%28title%3A%20learn%20or%20title%3A%20teach%20yourself%29&amp;amp;sz=25&amp;amp;pg=3/ref=s_b_np" style="background-color: white;"&gt;"hours"&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="background-color: white;"&gt; and got remarkably similar results: 253 more books, with 77 computer books followed by &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/0028638999/" style="background-color: white;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;Teach Yourself Grammar and Style in 24 Hours&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="background-color: white;"&gt; at number 78. Out of the top 200 total, 96% were computer books.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;div style="background-color: white;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: inherit;"&gt;The conclusion is that either people are in a big rush to learn about computers, or that computers are somehow fabulously easier to learn than anything else. There are no books on how to learn Beethoven, or Quantum Physics, or even Dog Grooming in a few days. Felleisen &lt;i&gt;et al.&lt;/i&gt; give a nod to this trend in their book &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.ccs.neu.edu/home/matthias/HtDP2e/index.html"&gt;How to Design Programs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;, when they say "Bad programming is easy. &lt;i&gt;Idiots&lt;/i&gt; can learn it in &lt;i&gt;21 days&lt;/i&gt;, even if they are &lt;i&gt;dummies&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="background-color: white;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: inherit;"&gt;Let's analyze what a title like &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Learn-C-Three-Days-Rachele/dp/1556227078"&gt;Learn C++ in Three Days&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt; could mean:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;ul style="background-color: white;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: inherit;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Learn:&lt;/b&gt; In 3 days you won't have time to write several significant programs, and learn from your successes and failures with them. You won't have time to work with an experienced programmer and understand what it is like to live in a C++ environment. In short, you won't have time to learn much. So the book can only be talking about a superficial familiarity, not a deep understanding. As Alexander Pope said, a little learning is a dangerous thing.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: inherit;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;C++:&lt;/b&gt; In 3 days you might be able to learn some of the syntax of C++ (if you already know another language), but you couldn't learn much about how to use the language. In short, if you were, say, a Basic programmer, you could learn to write programs in the style of Basic using C++ syntax, but you couldn't learn what C++ is actually good (and bad) for. So what's the point? &lt;a href="http://www-pu.informatik.uni-tuebingen.de/users/klaeren/epigrams.html"&gt;Alan Perlis&lt;/a&gt; once said: "A language that doesn't affect the way you think about programming, is not worth knowing". One possible point is that you have to learn a tiny bit of C++ (or more likely, something like JavaScript or Flash's Flex) because you need to interface with an existing tool to accomplish a specific task. But then you're not learning how to program; you're learning to accomplish that task.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: inherit;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;in Three Days:&lt;/b&gt; Unfortunately, this is not enough, as the next section shows.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2 style="background-color: white;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: inherit;"&gt;Teach Yourself Programming in Ten Years&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: inherit;"&gt;&lt;span style="background-color: white;"&gt;Researchers (&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/034531509X/" style="background-color: white;"&gt;Bloom (1985)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="background-color: white;"&gt;, &lt;/span&gt;Bryan &amp;amp; Harter (1899)&lt;span style="background-color: white;"&gt;, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/0805803092" style="background-color: white;"&gt;Hayes (1989)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="background-color: white;"&gt;, &lt;/span&gt;Simmon &amp;amp; Chase (1973)&lt;span style="background-color: white;"&gt;) have shown it takes about ten years to develop expertise in any of a wide variety of areas, including chess playing, music composition, telegraph operation, painting, piano playing, swimming, tennis, and research in neuropsychology and topology. The key is&lt;/span&gt;&lt;i style="background-color: white;"&gt;deliberative&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span style="background-color: white;"&gt; practice: not just doing it again and again, but challenging yourself with a task that is just beyond your current ability, trying it, analyzing your performance while and after doing it, and correcting any mistakes. Then repeat. And repeat again. There appear to be no real shortcuts: even Mozart, who was a musical prodigy at age 4, took 13 more years before he began to produce world-class music. In another genre, the Beatles seemed to burst onto the scene with a string of #1 hits and an appearance on the Ed Sullivan show in 1964. But they had been playing small clubs in Liverpool and Hamburg since 1957, and while they had mass appeal early on, their first great critical success,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;i style="background-color: white;"&gt;Sgt. Peppers&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span style="background-color: white;"&gt;, was released in 1967. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Outliers-Story-Success-Malcolm-Gladwell/dp/0316017922" style="background-color: white;"&gt;Malcolm Gladwell&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="background-color: white;"&gt; reports that a study of students at the Berlin Academy of Music compared the top, middle, and bottom third of the class and asked them how much they had practiced:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;blockquote style="background-color: white;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: inherit;"&gt;Everyone, from all three groups, started playing at roughly the same time - around the age of five. In those first few years, everyone practised roughly the same amount - about two or three hours a week. But around the age of eight real differences started to emerge. The students who would end up as the best in their class began to practise more than everyone else: six hours a week by age nine, eight by age 12, 16 a week by age 14, and up and up, until by the age of 20 they were practising well over 30 hours a week. By the age of 20, the elite performers had all totalled 10,000 hours of practice over the course of their lives. The merely good students had totalled, by contrast, 8,000 hours, and the future music teachers just over 4,000 hours.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;div style="background-color: white;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: inherit;"&gt;So it may be that 10,000 hours, not 10 years, is the magic number. (Henri Cartier-Bresson (1908-2004) said "Your first 10,000 photographs are your worst," but he shot more than one an hour.) Samuel Johnson (1709-1784) thought it took even longer: "Excellence in any department can be attained only by the labor of a lifetime; it is not to be purchased at a lesser price." And Chaucer (1340-1400) complained "the lyf so short, the craft so long to lerne." Hippocrates (c. 400BC) is known for the excerpt "ars longa, vita brevis", which is part of the longer quotation "Ars longa, vita brevis, occasio praeceps, experimentum periculosum, iudicium difficile", which in English renders as "Life is short, [the] craft long, opportunity fleeting, experiment treacherous, judgment difficult." Although in Latin, &lt;i&gt;ars&lt;/i&gt; can mean either art or craft, in the original Greek the word "techne" can only mean "skill", not "art".&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h2 style="background-color: white;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: inherit;"&gt;So You Want to be a Programmer&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div style="background-color: white;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: inherit;"&gt;Here's my recipe for programming success:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;ul style="background-color: white;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: inherit;"&gt;Get &lt;b&gt;interested&lt;/b&gt; in programming, and do some because it is fun. Make sure that it keeps being enough fun so that you will be willing to put in your ten years/10,000 hours.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: inherit;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Program&lt;/b&gt;. The best kind of learning is &lt;a href="http://www.engines4ed.org/hyperbook/nodes/NODE-120-pg.html"&gt;learning by doing&lt;/a&gt;. To put it more technically, "the maximal level of performance for individuals in a given domain is not attained automatically as a function of extended experience, but the level of performance can be increased even by highly experienced individuals as a result of deliberate efforts to improve." &lt;a href="http://www2.umassd.edu/swpi/DesignInCS/expertise.html"&gt;(p. 366)&lt;/a&gt; and "the most effective learning requires a well-defined task with an appropriate difficulty level for the particular individual, informative feedback, and opportunities for repetition and corrections of errors." (p. 20-21) The book &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/0521357349"&gt;Cognition in Practice: Mind, Mathematics, and Culture in Everyday Life&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt; is an interesting reference for this viewpoint.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: inherit;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Talk with&lt;/b&gt; other programmers; read other programs. This is more important than any book or training course.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: inherit;"&gt;If you want, put in four years at a &lt;b&gt;college&lt;/b&gt; (or more at a graduate school). This will give you access to some jobs that require credentials, and it will give you a deeper understanding of the field, but if you don't enjoy school, you can (with some dedication) get similar experience on your own or on the job. In any case, book learning alone won't be enough. "Computer science education cannot make anybody an expert programmer any more than studying brushes and pigment can make somebody an expert painter" says Eric Raymond, author of &lt;i&gt;The New Hacker's Dictionary&lt;/i&gt;. One of the best programmers I ever hired had only a High School degree; he's produced a lot of &lt;a href="http://www.xemacs.org/"&gt;great&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.mozilla.org/"&gt;software&lt;/a&gt;, has his own &lt;a href="http://groups.google.com/groups?q=alt.fan.jwz&amp;amp;meta=site%3Dgroups"&gt;news group&lt;/a&gt;, and made enough in stock options to buy his own &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/DNA_Lounge"&gt;nightclub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: inherit;"&gt;Work on &lt;b&gt;projects with&lt;/b&gt; other programmers. Be the best programmer on some projects; be the worst on some others. When you're the best, you get to test your abilities to lead a project, and to inspire others with your vision. When you're the worst, you learn what the masters do, and you learn what they don't like to do (because they make you do it for them).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: inherit;"&gt;Work on &lt;b&gt;projects &lt;i&gt;after&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; other programmers. Understand a program written by someone else. See what it takes to understand and fix it when the original programmers are not around. Think about how to design your programs to make it easier for those who will maintain them after you.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: inherit;"&gt;Learn at least a half dozen &lt;b&gt;programming languages&lt;/b&gt;. Include one language that supports class abstractions (like Java or C++), one that supports functional abstraction (like Lisp or ML), one that supports syntactic abstraction (like Lisp), one that supports declarative specifications (like Prolog or C++ templates), one that supports coroutines (like Icon or Scheme), and one that supports parallelism (like Sisal).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: inherit;"&gt;Remember that there is a "&lt;b&gt;computer&lt;/b&gt;" in "computer science". Know how long it takes your computer to execute an instruction, fetch a word from memory (with and without a cache miss), read consecutive words from disk, and seek to a new location on disk. (&lt;a href="http://norvig.com/21-days.html#answers"&gt;Answers here.&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: inherit;"&gt;Get involved in a language &lt;b&gt;standardization&lt;/b&gt; effort. It could be the ANSI C++ committee, or it could be deciding if your local coding style will have 2 or 4 space indentation levels. Either way, you learn about what other people like in a language, how deeply they feel so, and perhaps even a little about why they feel so.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: inherit;"&gt;Have the good sense to &lt;b&gt;get off&lt;/b&gt; the language standardization effort as quickly as possible.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: inherit;"&gt;&lt;span style="background-color: white;"&gt;With all that in mind, its questionable how far you can get just by book learning. Before my first child was born, I read all the &lt;/span&gt;&lt;i style="background-color: white;"&gt;How To&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span style="background-color: white;"&gt; books, and still felt like a clueless novice. 30 Months later, when my second child was due, did I go back to the books for a refresher? No. Instead, I relied on my personal experience, which turned out to be far more useful and reassuring to me than the thousands of pages written by experts.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;div style="background-color: white;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: inherit;"&gt;Fred Brooks, in his essay &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/No_Silver_Bullet"&gt;No Silver Bullet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt; identified a three-part plan for finding great software designers:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;ol style="background-color: white;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: inherit;"&gt;Systematically identify top designers as early as possible.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: inherit;"&gt;Assign a career mentor to be responsible for the development of the prospect and carefully keep a career file.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: inherit;"&gt;Provide opportunities for growing designers to interact and stimulate each other.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: inherit;"&gt;&lt;span style="background-color: white;"&gt;This assumes that some people already have the qualities necessary for being a great designer; the job is to properly coax them along. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="http://www-pu.informatik.uni-tuebingen.de/users/klaeren/epigrams.html" style="background-color: white;"&gt;Alan Perlis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="background-color: white;"&gt; put it more succinctly: "Everyone can be taught to sculpt: Michelangelo would have had to be taught how not to. So it is with the great programmers". Perlis is saying that the greats have some internal quality that transcends their training. But where does the quality come from? Is it innate? Or do they develop it through diligence? As Auguste Gusteau (the fictional chef in&lt;/span&gt;&lt;i style="background-color: white;"&gt;Ratatouille&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span style="background-color: white;"&gt;) puts it, "anyone can cook, but only the fearless can be great." I think of it more as willingness to devote a large portion of one's life to deliberative practice. But maybe &lt;/span&gt;&lt;i style="background-color: white;"&gt;fearless&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span style="background-color: white;"&gt; is a way to summarize that. Or, as Gusteau's critic, Anton Ego, says: "Not everyone can become a great artist, but a great artist can come from anywhere."&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;div style="background-color: white;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: inherit;"&gt;So go ahead and buy that Java/Ruby/Javascript/PHP book; you'll probably get some use out of it. But you won't change your life, or your real overall expertise as a programmer in 24 hours, days, or even weeks. How about working hard to continually improve over 24 months? Well, now you're starting to get somewhere...&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="background-color: white;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: inherit;"&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="background-color: white;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: inherit;"&gt;Credit: Written By &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="background-color: transparent;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://norvig.com/21-days.html" target="_blank"&gt;Peter Norvig&lt;/a&gt;,  Director of Research &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Google&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="background-color: white;"&gt;&lt;span style="background-color: transparent;"&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>amazing programming tips</category><category>anand reddy pandikunta</category><category>best programming tips</category><category>learn programming</category><category>personal blog of anand</category><category>peter norvig google</category><category>professional programming</category><category>programming for beginners</category><guid>http://www.avilpage.com/2014/01/avil-page-17-teach-yourself-programming.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2014 14:04:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>