<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Avil Page (startups)</title><link>http://www.avilpage.com</link><description></description><atom:link rel="self" href="http://www.avilpage.com/categories/startups.xml" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2016 14:08:14 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>https://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Start Up Job Boards In India</title><link>http://www.avilpage.com/2014/11/how-to-get-job-in-start-up-in-india.html</link><dc:creator>Chillar Anand</dc:creator><description>&lt;div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"&gt;Working with start ups is not only &lt;a href="http://www.zdnet.com/in/why-working-for-startups-is-worth-it-7000023025/" target="_blank"&gt;exciting &amp;amp; challenging&lt;/a&gt; but &lt;a href="http://www.quora.com/What-is-it-like-to-work-at-Social-Cops" target="_blank"&gt;its a lot of fun&lt;/a&gt; and there are lot of reasons why &lt;a href="http://yourstory.com/2014/05/working-with-startups/" target="_blank"&gt;working with a start up is the best thing you will ever do&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;While hunting for a start up job in Bangalore, these are some good job boards I came across.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;1. &lt;a href="https://hasjob.co/" target="_blank"&gt;Has Job&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;2. &lt;a href="http://jobs.yourstory.com/jobs/listing" target="_blank"&gt;Your Story Jobs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;3. &lt;a href="http://themorpheus.com/startup-jobs/" target="_blank"&gt;Startup Jobs @ The Morpheus&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;4. &lt;a href="http://jobs.nextbigwhat.com/" target="_blank"&gt;NextBigWhat Job Board&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;5. &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/forum/#!forum/headstart-network" target="_blank"&gt;HeadStart Network&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;6. &lt;a href="http://job.venturehire.co/" target="_blank"&gt;Venture Hire&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;7. &lt;a href="http://dreamstarts.in/" target="_blank"&gt;Dream Starts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;8. &lt;a href="http://blrstartups.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Bangalore Startups&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;9. &lt;a href="http://www.f6s.com/jobs" target="_blank"&gt;f6s Jobs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bangalore</category><category>startups</category><guid>http://www.avilpage.com/2014/11/how-to-get-job-in-start-up-in-india.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2014 16:23:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Start Up Companies In Banglore</title><link>http://www.avilpage.com/2014/01/list-of-bangalore-start-up-companies.html</link><dc:creator>Chillar Anand</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;After completion of my B.Tech in 2013, I started looking for start-up companies in Bangalore and here are a few of them I came to know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://peppersquare.com"&gt;Peppersquare&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Founded in 2002, we are a happily independent digital agency from Bangalore. We work as an extended team to deliver digital services to enterprises, agencies and emerging companies. Our proprietary Digital Maturity Index measures and monitors where brands stand in the digital business future, and offers effective engagement to tap new markets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://toptomato.in"&gt;Toptomato&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Toptomato is a one-stop online solution for all household needs, spanning the FMCG portfolio of foods, personal care and household care products, thus ushering in a new era of convenient grocery shopping. Leveraging on new-technologies and business strategies, Toptomato is committed to bring in superior service and customer delight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://foofys.com"&gt;Foofys&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are a mobile app creation company that also provides digital design services.We see ourselves as crusaders of providing relevant information and this has been our constant striving, creating sustainable solutions that give you the information you need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://hifives.in"&gt;Hifives&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HiFives is the flagship product of DealsNow Consumer Solutions Private Limited, an employee applications company. DealsNow develops corporate solutions for employee rewards, recognition, gamification, engagement, collaboration, productivity, work-life balance and other employee focused applications, that can be deployed on the cloud, corporate intranets and mobile platforms. It was founded by IIT-IIM alumni in 2010.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://frrole.com"&gt;Frrole&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frrole's Social Intelligence Platform currently analyzes almost half a billion data units every month, using the derived insights to create solutions for brands, media and entertainment verticals. We take pride in our ability to answer fuzzy questions, when almost all traditional data analytics stops at providing statistical and keyword based answers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://fungroo.com"&gt;Fungroo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A company started by IIM Bangalore Graduates having a customer engagement platform that captures customer feedback in real time from anywhere in this world and helps organizations gain customer insights to take actions at the right time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Address:
Fungaroo, C/O Alitum management solutions pvt. ltd, #32, Kormangala inner ring road Bangalore, Karnataka : 560047&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://getmeenabled.com"&gt;Getmeenabled&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GME Disablity Enablers is an online store for disability equipments and devices (Registration No:Firm/GNR/48/2013-14). GME Disability Enablers mission is to make available world class disability equipments to persons with disability at the door step. This online venture was setup to bridge the gap in availability of suitable devices that empower the disabled to lead independent lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://promptcloud.com"&gt;Promptcloud&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PromptCloud is a Bangalore-based firm dealing with Big Data solutions; where an integral part is web crawling and data extraction. We use cloud computing solutions to facilitate our Data as a Service platform. We work with clients from a range of domains including travel, finance, health-care, marketing, analytics and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://metaome.com"&gt;Metaome&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Metaome is a "Big Data" company for the life sciences. We have an agile, customer focused product development strategy and are committed to help scientists glean the best insights and value from data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://qubole.com"&gt;Qubole&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Qubole we’re developing the next generation cloud data platform. With an unparalleled understanding of the cloud and a can do attitude we’re addressing today’s challenges of storing and managing data to create the future: a fast, easy and reliable path to turning Big Data into business insight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://dreamstarts.in"&gt;Dreamstarts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DreamStarts.in is a job search engine for Indian Startups where Startups post job vacancies and potential employees (Talents) apply to the jobs for free. DreamStarts.in targets elite professionals, Marketing Gurus, freelance designers / developers and talented students in India.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://relecura.com"&gt;Relecura&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Relecura is developed by INDUS TechInnovations, a technology company developing innovative products based on knowledge discovery. We provide software solutions to mine knowledge from relevant data. We have developed application-specific technology platforms to organize and deliver knowledge solutions. These enable customers in different verticals to better explore, comprehend, and glean insights from the large and rapidly growing data sets that are of importance in their domains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://emswebtech.com"&gt;EMSwebtech&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EMS Webtech is a leading IT solutions company. We provide full-cycle services in the areas of software development, web-based enterprise solutions, web application, portal development, Ecommerce developement, Graphic Design and internet marketing services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://mydeals247.com"&gt;Mydeals247&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MyDeals247 offers three unique business models:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Real-Time MarketPlace (Buy / Sell Model) - No inventory on the website - everything starts from the consumer interest - system notifies the consumer requests to all the sellers whoever selling the particular product or service along with the consumer's budget - sellers make offers against the consumer request along with the offer expiry times - system picks only the top 5 best offers (by lowest price) - totally real-time and rank order changes based on the offers received by the sellers - consumers takes advantage of the best offer and purchase the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Volume Based Discounts - deals with only 5 star rated retailers - focus on general house-hold items, entertainment, education, local events, amusement parks, professional training, and services companies - consumer can share the vouchers with friends and colleagues - volume based purchase only - buy more save big!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Introduces personalized Ad display and ‘Pay Per Lead’ model - Displays the local Ads based on the consumer’s interest within the local city at any given point in time. For instance, if someone is looking for the footware and watches in San Francisco, system consolidates all the local Ads relevant to footwear and watches under "San Francisco Talks about..."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://yourstory.com"&gt;Yourstory&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;YourStory is India’s no.1 media platform for entrepreneurs, dedicated to passionately championing and promoting the entrepreneurial ecosystem in India.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;YourStory was started in October 2008 by Shradha Sharma, who has held senior positions in leading media organizations like The Times of India and CNBC TV18. Today, YourStory is driven by Shradha’s vision to create a hub for thousands of entrepreneurs across India, by providing them with critical value-additions like visibility, business networking, corporate partnerships, growth opportunities and investor connections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://inktalks.com"&gt;INKtalks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To create a community of like-minded peers on unconventional ‘career’ paths, from any field. The experience of being a change-maker is often isolating, as it can lack the financial security, clarity of direction and social network that come with traditional jobs. Being an INK Fellow provides the peer-support necessary to take brilliant work to the next level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To leverage their impact, through mentorship, support, networks and specially designed opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To provide them a platform for discovery and exposure like no other, so that our change-makers gain access to potential customers, funding opportunities, accolades and other forms of support critical to their development and success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://quicksearch.in"&gt;QuickSearch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are a local search service focusing on tier 4-5 cities in India. Currently focussing on Chhattisgarh, we are already handling enquiries for 12 odd cities in Chhattisgarh, MP and Jharkhand. With 100k+ data points, many of which are exclusive to us, we aim to put every neighbourhood shop and business online. Imagine searching for and finding online the number of your neighbourhood store even in relatively smaller cities in Jharkhand, Chhattisgarh etc! "&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://housingman.com"&gt;HousingMan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"HousingMan brings property buyers and sellers together in one transparent marketplace where both sides get equal opportunity to realize benefits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Capabilities
Tools for buyers and property developers/builders to list, browse, research, bid, place discount offers, and track/manage residential property information —all in one place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Transparency
A “more windows, fewer walls” approach to real estate: we believe in making information easy to find, keeping all parties clued in, and creating smooth transactions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Choices
Users have control, whether customizing listings, choosing to accept an offer, or deciding when to jump into an auction."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://mplentis.com"&gt;Mplentis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MPLENTIS is a WEB Development and SEO Company headquartered in Bangalore, Offering affordable website Design and Development, Responsive Web Design and Development, E-Commerce websites, Content Management System, Content Writing, SEO, Logo Design, Brochure Design and other printing solutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.doodleblue.com/"&gt;doodleblue&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right from mobile application development, web application development, UI/UX, to digital marketing, doodleblue provides a one-stop solution for all your digital needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feel free to suggest any other companies &lt;a href="http://goo.gl/forms/ne0kRY6LdQc1XP6O2"&gt;to add to this list&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bangalore</category><category>startups</category><guid>http://www.avilpage.com/2014/01/list-of-bangalore-start-up-companies.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2014 16:52:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>