<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Avil Page (2019)</title><link>http://avilpage.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://avilpage.com/2019/rss.xml" type="application/rss+xml" rel="self"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2019 15:42:28 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Why My Grandma Can Recall 100+ Phone Numbers, But We Can't</title><link>http://avilpage.com/2019/05/total-recall-grandma-phone-numbers.html</link><dc:creator>Chillar Anand</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;On a leisure evening, as I was chit chatting with my grandma, my phone started ringing. Some one who is not in my contacts is calling me. As I was wondering who the heck is calling, my grandma just glanced at my screen and said, "Its you uncle Somu, pick up the phone". I was dumbstruck by this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later that evening, I asked my grandma to recall the phone numbers she remembers. She recalled 30+ phone numbers and she was able to recognize 100+ phone numbers based on the last 4 digits of the mobile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That came as a surprise for me as I don't even remember 10+ phone numbers now. Most of the smart phone users don't remember family and friends phone numbers anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A decade back, I used to remember most of my relatives and friends phone numbers even though I didn't had a phone. My grandma used to use a mini notebook to write all the phone numbers. I was worried about this mini notebook as it can get lost easily and it is always hard to find when required.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since my grandma didn't have any contacts in her phone, she gets a glimpse of number every time someone calls her. She also dials the number every time she has to call someone. With this habit she is able to memorize all the numbers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I, on the other hand started using a smart phone which has all the contacts. I search my contacts by name when I have to dial someone and there is no need to dial the number. Also whenever someone call me, their name gets displayed in large letters and I never get to focus on the number. Due to this, I don't remember any of the phone numbers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After this revelation, I started an experiment by disabling contact permissions for dialer app. With this, I am forced to type the number or select appropriate number from the call history and dial it. This was a bit uncomfortable at first. Soon I got used to it as recognized more and more numbers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This might seem unnecessary in the smart phone age. But when you are traveling or when your phone gets switched off, it's hard to contact people. Even if someone gives their phone, it is of no use if I don't remember any numbers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also it is important to remember phone numbers of family and friends which might be needed in case of emergencies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>grandma</category><category>life-tips</category><guid>http://avilpage.com/2019/05/total-recall-grandma-phone-numbers.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2019 15:51:21 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Switching Hosts With Bookmarklets - Web Development Tips</title><link>http://avilpage.com/2019/05/environment-bookmarklet-web-development-tips.html</link><dc:creator>Chillar Anand</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;When debugging an issue related to web development projects, which is inconsistent between environments (local, development, QA, staging and production), we have to frequently switch between them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we are debugging something on the home page, then we can just bookmark the host URLs. We can switch between them by clicking on the relevant bookmark. Some browsers provide autocompletion for bookmarks. So we can type a few characters and then select the relevant URL from suggestions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When debugging an issue on some other page like &lt;a href="http://avilpage.com/2019/05/environment-bookmarklet-web-development-tips.html"&gt;https://avilpage.com/validate/books/?name=darwin&amp;amp;year=2019&lt;/a&gt;, which has URL path and query param, switching between enviroment becomes tedious. To switch to local environment, we have to manually replace the hostname with localhost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To avoid this, we can use a bookmarklet to switch the hosts. A &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bookmarklet"&gt;bookmarklet&lt;/a&gt; is a bookmark which contains a JavaScript code snippet in its URL. This code snippet will be executed when the bookmarklet is clicked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lets create a bookmarklet to replace host in the URL with &lt;a href="http://localhost:8000"&gt;http://localhost:8000&lt;/a&gt;. Create new bookmark called &lt;code&gt;To Local&lt;/code&gt; and in the URL add the following snippet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="code literal-block"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nx"&gt;javascript&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="kd"&gt;function&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;()&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nb"&gt;window&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nx"&gt;location&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nx"&gt;replace&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;"http://localhost:8000"&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nb"&gt;window&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nx"&gt;location&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nx"&gt;pathname&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nb"&gt;window&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nx"&gt;location&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nx"&gt;search&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;);&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;}())&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;


&lt;p&gt;If we click on &lt;code&gt;To Local&lt;/code&gt; bookmarklet, it will redirect the current active page to localhost URL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can create one more bookmarklet to switch to production. Create a bookmarklet called &lt;code&gt;To Production&lt;/code&gt; and add the following snippet in the URL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="code literal-block"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nx"&gt;javascript&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="kd"&gt;function&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;()&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nb"&gt;window&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nx"&gt;location&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nx"&gt;replace&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;"http://avilpage.com"&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nb"&gt;window&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nx"&gt;location&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nx"&gt;pathname&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nb"&gt;window&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nx"&gt;location&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nx"&gt;search&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;);&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;}())&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;


&lt;p&gt;We can create similar bookmarklets to switch to other enviroments. Now, switching between enviroments on any page is as easy as clicking a button.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>chrome</category><category>web-development</category><category>web-development-tips</category><guid>http://avilpage.com/2019/05/environment-bookmarklet-web-development-tips.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2019 15:40:52 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>A Short Guide To Debugging PostgreSQL Triggers</title><link>http://avilpage.com/2019/04/how-to-debug-postgres-triggers.html</link><dc:creator>Chillar Anand</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Introduction&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.postgresql.org/docs/9.1/sql-createtrigger.html"&gt;PostgreSQL triggers&lt;/a&gt; will associate a &lt;code&gt;function&lt;/code&gt; to a table for an event. If multiple triggers of the same kind are defined for the same event, they will executed in alphabetical order by name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article we will see how to debug PostgreSQL triggers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Triggers&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First ensure triggers are enabled on the required tables for INSERT/UPDATE/DELETE events. We can check available triggers by running the following query.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="code literal-block"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;SELECT&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;FROM&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;information_schema&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;triggers&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;


&lt;p&gt;We can also use &lt;code&gt;EXPLAIN&lt;/code&gt; to show triggers which are executed for an event by running relevant queries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;PostgreSQL Logging&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After ensuring triggers are applied correctly, set logging level for postgresql server and client in postgres.conf file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="code literal-block"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;#&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;let&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;server&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;log&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;all&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;queries&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;log_statement&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s1"&gt;'all'&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="o"&gt;#&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;set&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;client&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;message&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;to&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;log&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;level&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;client_min_messages&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;log&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Restart postgresql to reflect configuration changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="code literal-block"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="c1"&gt;# Linux&lt;/span&gt;
sudo service postgres restart

&lt;span class="c1"&gt;# Mac&lt;/span&gt;
brew services restart postgres
&lt;/pre&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Tail the logs and check if queries are executing correctly with appropriate values.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Triggers Logging&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After enabling logging for PostgreSQL, we can &lt;a href="https://www.postgresql.org/docs/9.0/plpgsql-errors-and-messages.html"&gt;raise messages/errors in triggers&lt;/a&gt; so that we can see if any unexpected things are happening at any point in the trigger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="code literal-block"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;RAISE&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s1"&gt;'Updating row with ID: %'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;id&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;RAISE&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;division_by_zero&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;RAISE&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;WARNING&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s1"&gt;'Unable to deleted record'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;


&lt;p&gt;This makes sure triggers are executing as expected and if there are any warnings/errors, it will log a message.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;SQL/PostgreSQL Gotchas&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though queries and triggers are executing correctly, we might not see the desired result because of potentially suprising behaviour of PostgreSQL. There are a some scenarios where PostgreSQL seems to be not working at first but it actually is the expected behaviour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unquoted object names will be treated as lower case. &lt;code&gt;SELECT FOO FROM bar&lt;/code&gt; will become &lt;code&gt;SELECT foo FROM bar&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Comparing nullable fields. This might yield strange results as &lt;code&gt;NULL != NULL&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PostgreSQL uses POSIX offsets. For &lt;code&gt;04:21:42 UTC+01&lt;/code&gt;, +1  means the timezone is west of Greenwich.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By being aware of common PostgreSQL gotchas and enabling logging for PostgreSQL client, server &amp;amp; triggers, pinpointing the bug in triggers becomes easy. Once the bug is identified, appropriate action can be taken to fix the issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- links --&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>database</category><category>debug</category><category>postgresql</category><guid>http://avilpage.com/2019/04/how-to-debug-postgres-triggers.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2019 15:51:21 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Essential PyCharm (Intellij) Plugins To Improve Productivity</title><link>http://avilpage.com/2019/03/intellij-pycharm-plugins-productivity.html</link><dc:creator>Chillar Anand</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;As per 2019 &lt;a href="https://www.jetbrains.com/research/python-developers-survey-2018/#development-tools"&gt;JetBrains survery&lt;/a&gt;, PyCharm is the most widely used(36%) IDE for Python development. Eventhough PyCharm comes with lot of built in features, there are a lot of plugins available for PyCharm and other Intellij IDEs. In this article, we will see some plugins which will boost our productivity during development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Highlight Bracket Pair&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of manually scanning where a bracket starts/ends, &lt;a href="https://plugins.jetbrains.com/plugin/10465-highlightbracketpair"&gt;Highlight Bracket Pair&lt;/a&gt; will automatically hightlight the bracket pairs based on cursor position.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Rainbow Brackets&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Highlight Bracket Pair will hightlight the bracket pair around the cursor. When there are multiple bracket pairs deeply nested, &lt;a href="https://plugins.jetbrains.com/plugin/10080-rainbow-brackets"&gt;Rainbow Brackets&lt;/a&gt; will highlight matching bracket pairs with matching rainbow colors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Grep Console&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When running a django/flask server or any Python script which generates lot of output, it is hard to filter out required output on console. &lt;a href="https://plugins.jetbrains.com/plugin/7125-grep-console"&gt;Grep Console&lt;/a&gt; can filter or highlight output based on specific conditions which makes it easier to debug the code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Save Actions&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of manually optimizing imports or reformating code when changes are made, we can use &lt;a href="https://plugins.jetbrains.com/plugin/7642-save-actions"&gt;Save Actions&lt;/a&gt; which will automatically run a set of actions on every file save.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Key Promoter&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are new to PyCharm or an experienced user who is using mouse instead of key board shortcuts, &lt;a href="https://plugins.jetbrains.com/plugin/9792-key-promoter-x"&gt;Key Promoter&lt;/a&gt; will show relevant key board shortcut when mouse is used inside IDE. This provides an easy way to learn keyboard shortcuts faster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;String Manipulation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To convert lower case letters to upper case letter, &lt;a href="https://plugins.jetbrains.com/plugin/2162-string-manipulation"&gt;String manipulation plugin&lt;/a&gt; will be useful. In addition to lower/upper case conversion, it also provides options to convert to cameCase, kebab-case, PascalCase etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Ace Jump&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To move caret to a particular position in the editor without mouse,
&lt;a href="https://plugins.jetbrains.com/plugin/7086-acejump"&gt;AceJump plugin&lt;/a&gt; will be useful. It allows to quickly navigate the caret to any position in the editor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are some plugins which will boost developers productivity while writing and debugging code in PyCharm or other JetBrains IDE.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>django</category><category>pycharm</category><category>python</category><guid>http://avilpage.com/2019/03/intellij-pycharm-plugins-productivity.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2019 15:51:21 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Django Tips &amp; Tricks #12 - Automatically Set CSRF Token in Postman</title><link>http://avilpage.com/2019/02/django-tips-csrf-token-postman-curl.html</link><dc:creator>Chillar Anand</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Introduction&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Django has inbuilt &lt;a href="https://docs.djangoproject.com/en/dev/ref/csrf/"&gt;CSRF protection&lt;/a&gt; mechanism for requests via unsafe methods to prevent &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cross-site_request_forgery"&gt;Cross Site Request Forgeries&lt;/a&gt;. When CSRF protection is enabled on AJAX POST methods, &lt;code&gt;X-CSRFToken&lt;/code&gt; header should be sent in the request.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.getpostman.com"&gt;Postman&lt;/a&gt; is one of the widely used tool for testing APIs. In this article, we will see how to set csrf token and update it automatically in Postman.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;CSRF Token In Postman&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Django sets &lt;code&gt;csrftoken&lt;/code&gt; cookie on login. After logging in, we can see the csrf token from cookies in the Postman.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align="center"&gt;
&lt;img src="http://avilpage.com/images/django-csrf-postman1.png"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can grab this token and set it in headers manually.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align="center"&gt;
&lt;img src="http://avilpage.com/images/django-csrf-postman2.png"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But this token has to be manually changed when it expires. This process becomes tedious to do it on an expiration basis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead, we can use Postman scripting feature to extract token from cookie and set it to an environment variable. In &lt;code&gt;Test&lt;/code&gt; section of postman, add these lines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="code literal-block"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="kd"&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nx"&gt;xsrfCookie&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nx"&gt;postman&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nx"&gt;getResponseCookie&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;"csrftoken"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="nx"&gt;postman&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nx"&gt;setEnvironmentVariable&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;'csrftoken'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nx"&gt;xsrfCookie&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nx"&gt;value&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;


&lt;p&gt;This extracts csrf token and sets it to an evironment variable called &lt;code&gt;csrftoken&lt;/code&gt; in the current environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align="center"&gt;
&lt;img src="http://avilpage.com/images/django-csrf-postman3.png"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now in our requests, we can use this variable to set the header.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align="center"&gt;
&lt;img src="http://avilpage.com/images/django-csrf-postman4.png"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the token expires, we just need to login again and csrf token gets updated automatically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article we have seen how to set and renew csrftoken automatically in Postman. We can follow similar techniques on other API clients like CURL or httpie to set csrf token.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>api</category><category>django</category><category>django-tips-tricks</category><category>python</category><guid>http://avilpage.com/2019/02/django-tips-csrf-token-postman-curl.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 15:51:21 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>