<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Avil Page (2020)</title><link>http://avilpage.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://avilpage.com/2020/rss.xml" type="application/rss+xml" rel="self"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 15:42:07 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Setup Self-hosted Comment System For Static Sites</title><link>http://avilpage.com/2020/01/commenting-system-for-static-sites.html</link><dc:creator>Chillar Anand</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Introduction&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This blog &lt;a href="https://avilpage.com"&gt;AvilPage&lt;/a&gt; is generated by &lt;a href="https://pypi.org/project/Nikola/"&gt;Nikola&lt;/a&gt;, a static site generator. Since this is a static site, to setup up comments it has to depend on hosted commenting systems like
&lt;a href="https://disqus.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Disqus&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="https://just-comments.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;JustComments&lt;/a&gt;
etc or self-host an open source system like  &lt;a href="https://github.com/coralproject/talk"&gt;Coral&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://github.com/eduardoboucas/staticman"&gt;StaticMan&lt;/a&gt; etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hosted systems have no maintainance but has privacy and pricing issues. With self hosted systems, there will be complete access to data but maintainance is an issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coral commenting system provides 1-click deployment to Heroku which reduces maintainance effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Setting Up Coral&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Heroku provides free hosting for hobby projects. Coral project provides a template to deploy to Heorku directly. Once the app is deployed, we can configure comment system from the coral admin page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once it is configured, we have to embed JS snippet available at &lt;a href="https://docs.coralproject.net/talk/v5/integrating/cms/"&gt;Coral CMS integration&lt;/a&gt; to the static site to render comments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we use Heroku free tier, Dynos will sleep when there is no traffic. Next time when someone posts a comment, it will take a while for the dyno to respond. To prevent we can setup a monitor on Uptimerobot or Pingdom so that it will make a request to heroku app every ~20 minutes. This will consume Dyno hours but coral app response will be faster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Self-hosting a comment system is easy with Coral. There are other hosted alternatives to Disqus but due to privacy and pricing concerns, I wanted to use self-hosted commenting system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to &lt;a href="http://blog.kiranruth.com"&gt;Master Ruth&lt;/a&gt; for nudging and helping me in setting up comment system on this blog.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>meta</category><category>static-site</category><guid>http://avilpage.com/2020/01/commenting-system-for-static-sites.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 01:47:12 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>