<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Avil Page (Posts about blogging)</title><link>http://avilpage.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://avilpage.com/tags/cat_blogging.xml" type="application/rss+xml" rel="self"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2020 15:39:15 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Why Blog Posts Are Better Than Scientific Papers?</title><link>http://avilpage.com/2017/01/blog_posts_are_better_than_scientific_papers/</link><dc:creator>Chillar Anand</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Titus Brown wrote a blog post on why &lt;a href="http://ivory.idyll.org/blog/2017-top-ten-reasons-blog-posts.html"&gt;blog posts are better than scientific papers&lt;/a&gt;. Here are few more reasons for that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fast&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Publishing blog posts is lightning fast(how fast can you type?). You can just publish it with a click after writing. However with scientific papers you have to wait months to get your work published.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Mutability&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blog posts are easy to edit. If you are using a version controlled system like git, any one can easily collaborate. You can also leave comments on (most) blog posts and can have discussion with the author and/or others. Scientific papers once published are hard to change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;No Gatekeepers&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To publish blog posts, you can setup your own blog or use services like &lt;a href="http://medium.com"&gt;medium&lt;/a&gt;. There are no gatekeepers who says that you can't publish a blog post because they thinks its not worth it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Organic&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blog posts tend to be casual and organic. You can crack a joke and readers will enjoy it. Scientific papers are formal. You spray some sarcasm and your paper never gets published.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>blogging</category><category>research</category><guid>http://avilpage.com/2017/01/blog_posts_are_better_than_scientific_papers/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2017 17:03:38 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Some Frequently Asked Questions About This Blog</title><link>http://avilpage.com/2014/01/avil-page-frequently-asked-questions.html</link><dc:creator>Chillar Anand</dc:creator><description>&lt;div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"&gt;Q: What is Avilpage?&lt;br&gt;A: Just an e-page to write my personal stuff.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Q: Why there are no comments on this blog?&lt;br&gt;A: Comments are a good way of interacting and there are many benefits with that but they take a lot of time and I will loose the focus on the topics, so I disabled comments on my blog.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Q: No sharing buttons?&lt;br&gt;A: I just removed them and I don't want them here. If you really liked an article, send a message or a mail to your friends about that. That will be great.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Q: No Ads?&lt;br&gt;A: Unlike my previous blogs, I am not placing any ads here. I am getting a bad feeling about the ads and soon I will remove the ads from my previous blogs also.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Q: No Search?&lt;br&gt;A: Yeah no. Lets say you want to search about "movies". You can go to List of Avil Pages, press "Ctrl + F" and search for movies. If You need a better search go to Google and search "site:avilpage.com movies"&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Q: Why there is no subscribe button?&lt;br&gt;A: I don't want it to be there. I don't want a mail delivered to your inbox whenever I wrote some nonsense. When you have some free time, just check out here.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Q: I need to talk to you. How to contact you?&lt;br&gt;A: Ok, &lt;a href="http://www.avilpage.com/2014/01/avil-page-9-lets-talk.html"&gt;Lets Talk.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Q: Tech details of blog?&lt;br&gt;A: Domain registered with Godaddy and hosted on blogger platform. Using Simple Template.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>blogging</category><guid>http://avilpage.com/2014/01/avil-page-frequently-asked-questions.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2014 11:47:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>