<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Avil Page (Posts about 2022)</title><link>http://avilpage.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://avilpage.com/tags/cat_2022.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 07:33:00 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Using Frappe Framework As REST API Generator</title><link>http://avilpage.com/2022/04/frappe-framework-rest-api-generator.html</link><dc:creator>Chillar Anand</dc:creator><description>&lt;h4&gt;Introduction&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a company plans to build a mobile application and/or a web application, they need to create REST APIs to store data. This is a common requirement for CRUD applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the Python ecosystem, there are several projects like Django Rest Framework, Flask-RESTful, FastApi which does the heavy lifting of implementing REST APIs. In other ecosystems, there are similar projects/frameworks for this job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;REST API Generators&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By using the above mentioned frameworks, developers can build REST APIs at a faster rate. Still, developers have to develop and maintain code for these APIs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To avoid even this work, there are REST API generators like postgrest&lt;sup id="fnref:postgrest"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="http://avilpage.com/2022/04/frappe-framework-rest-api-generator.html#fn:postgrest"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, prest which can instantly generate REST APIs by inspecting database schema. With these, developers just have to design the DB schema and these tools take care of generating APIs without writing a single line of code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this post, let us see how Frappe framework can be used as a REST API generator and what are the advantages of using Frappe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Frappe Framework&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frappe framework is meta data driven low code, web framework written in Python and Javascript.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Web UI&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frappe framework provides web UI to create models(called doctypes in Frappe) and it provides REST API&lt;sup id="fnref:rest_api"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="http://avilpage.com/2022/04/frappe-framework-rest-api-generator.html#fn:rest_api"&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; for all the models out of the box.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no need to write manual SQL queries to manage schema. With some training even non-developers can even manage models in Frappe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Roles &amp;amp; Permissions&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With traditional API generators, managing roles &amp;amp; permissions involves additional development and maintenance costs. Frappes comes with an authentication system and it has support for role based permissions out of the box. From the web UI, users can manage roles &amp;amp; permissions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Hooks&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though REST API generators give API out of the box, there will be scenarios where custom business logic needs to be hooked in for various events.
In such scenarios, developers end up using an alternate framework/tool to manage hooks and business logic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frappe provides server scripts by which arbitrary python code can be executed dynamically based on model events. There is no need to set up another framework for these things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Utilities&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frappe framework comes with a lot of utilities like Job Queues, Schedulers, Admin interface, socket.io etc. As the project grows and the need evolves, Frappe has all the common utilities that are required for a web application development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a company wants to build a solution to a problem, it should focus most of the time in solving that problem instead of wasting their time on building CRUD interfaces or REST APIs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frappe framework was designed to rapidly build web applications with low code. If you need a REST API generator and some additional functionality for the REST APIs, Frappe framework fits the bill and reduces a lot of development time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="footnote"&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:postgrest"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/PostgREST/postgrest"&gt;https://github.com/PostgREST/postgrest&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="http://avilpage.com/2022/04/frappe-framework-rest-api-generator.html#fnref:postgrest" title="Jump back to footnote 1 in the text"&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:rest_api"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://frappeframework.com/docs/user/en/api/rest"&gt;https://frappeframework.com/docs/user/en/api/rest&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="http://avilpage.com/2022/04/frappe-framework-rest-api-generator.html#fnref:rest_api" title="Jump back to footnote 2 in the text"&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>http://avilpage.com/2022/04/frappe-framework-rest-api-generator.html</guid><pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 13:31:53 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Adding Fuzzy Search To Frappe Framework</title><link>http://avilpage.com/2022/03/fuzzy-search-frappe-framework.html</link><dc:creator>Chillar Anand</dc:creator><description>&lt;h4&gt;Introduction&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As software developers, we use fuzzy search a lot especially when using Emacs or any other editors/IDEs. For example to search a file called &lt;code&gt;patient_history.js&lt;/code&gt;, in the editor, we can just type &lt;code&gt;pah&lt;/code&gt; and editor will narrow it down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://avilpage.com/images/frappe-fuzzy-search-1.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is quite handy as we can open any file with just few characters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FF is a low code, open source, web framework in Python and Javascript. All sites built with FF will have a global search bar(aka awesome bar) as shown below. Here, we can search for doctypes, reports, pages etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://avilpage.com/images/frappe-fuzzy-search-2.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To open &lt;code&gt;Patient History&lt;/code&gt;, we have to type almost the entire text in search bar. If we type &lt;code&gt;pah&lt;/code&gt; like we have typed in the editor, it won't show any results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://avilpage.com/images/frappe-fuzzy-search-3.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead, we can add fuzzy search here so that we can search for any item with just a frew key strokes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Fuzzy Search&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many third party packages which implement fuzzy search in programming languages. However we can't use any of these fuzzy search packages directly. These editors internally use a scoring algorithm to rank the results and display results based on score.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It internally considers many factors mentioned below for scoring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Matched letters&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CamelCase letters&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;snake_case letters&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consecutive matching letters&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can come up with a scoring mechanism for these factors and based on the matches, we can rank the results. I have implemented a custom fuzzy search alogirthm based on the above factors but it was slow and results were not good in some cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I stumbled up this &lt;a href="https://github.com/forrestthewoods/lib_fts/blob/master/code/fts_fuzzy_match.js"&gt;fts_fuzzy_match&lt;/a&gt; implementation. This is a reverse engineered implementation of sublime text fuzzy search and it has a detailed scoring mechanism as well. It assigns negative ranking to mismatched letters and bonus points for consecutive matches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This works well and is as effective as most IDEs search. Now that there is a solid fuzzy search, all we need to do is hook this up in FF.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FF internally has a fuzzy search function and we can directly hook it up here as shown here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After that, we can search for anything in just few key strokes. For example to open patient history, we can just type &lt;code&gt;pah&lt;/code&gt; and it will show results like this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://avilpage.com/images/frappe-fuzzy-search-4.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fuzzy search in editors/IDEs is quite handy and when we bring to other places like FF or any other search bar, it improves search experience a lot.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>frappe-framework</category><category>js</category><guid>http://avilpage.com/2022/03/fuzzy-search-frappe-framework.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 16:00:33 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Using Frappe Framework As An Integration Engine</title><link>http://avilpage.com/2022/02/frappe-framework-mirth.html</link><dc:creator>Chillar Anand</dc:creator><description>&lt;h4&gt;Introduction&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In healthcare orgainsations, data exchange between systems is complicated and has interopolabilty issues. Integration engines are widely used in healthcare industry for bi-directional data transfer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, let us look at the advantages of using interface engines and how Frappe Framework can be used as an interface engine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Integration Engines&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a traditional agile development approach, building a new interface might take weeks/months. With an integration engine, a new interface can be replicated in a matter of hours with little or no scripting at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creating a REST API, listening to a webhook, transforming a data between channels, broadcasting a message, sending/receiving HL7 messages or any other commonly performed task can be implemented in integration engine without much effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to this integration engines like &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mirth_Connect"&gt;Mirth Connect&lt;/a&gt; are widely used in healthcare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://avilpage.com/images/mirth-integration-engine.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The above diagram shows usage of integration engine in a healthcare orgainsation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Frappe Framework&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frappe Framework is a low code web application framework with batteries included. Even though Frappe is lablled as a framework, it can be used as an integration engine as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It provides REST APIs out of the box for all the models(called doctypes in Frappe). Users can create custom APIs using &lt;a href="https://frappeframework.com/docs/v13/user/en/api/rest"&gt;server scripts&lt;/a&gt; and it has support for webhooks as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Users can schedule custom cron jobs, setup emails, enable data transformations and other tasks without much coding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One feature Frappe Framework lacks when compared to integration engines is sending/receiving HL7 messages on ad-hoc ports. This feature is not available out of the box. Users need to develop a custom app or use any 3rd party app for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/frappe/healthcare"&gt;Frappe Healthcare&lt;/a&gt; is an HIS(Healthcare Information System) built on top of Frappe/ERPNext. If a hospital is using Frappe Healthcare, then there won't be a need to use integration engine as Frappe framework can take care of most of these things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://avilpage.com/images/frappe-his.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The above diagram shows usage of Frappe Healthcare as HIS in a healthcare orgainsation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In healthcare, integration engines are used extensively to tackle data exchange between systems. Due to its low-code development and batteries included approach, even though Frappe is a web application framework, it can be used as an integration engine as well.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>frappe-framework</category><category>healthcare</category><guid>http://avilpage.com/2022/02/frappe-framework-mirth.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 16:01:40 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>On Resuming Writing Challenge</title><link>http://avilpage.com/2022/01/resuming-writing-challenge.html</link><dc:creator>Chillar Anand</dc:creator><description>&lt;p align="center"&gt;
&lt;img height="300" width="800" src="http://avilpage.com/images/writing_challenge.jpg"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align="center"&gt;
Photo by Kaboompics on Pexels
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2018, I decided to write at least one blog post per month throughout the year. Even though I tried to write posts every month, I couldn't publish anything in few months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2019, I went a step ahead and made a legal(?) agreement with a friend. I paid him 1,00,000 rupees and told him that he could keep the money as a reward if I failed to write a blog post every month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This agreement kept me on my toes. I didn't miss writing a single month in 2019. I stayed awake on the last days of the month to finish and publish the post before midnight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2020, I took up the challenge again and I was able to write at least one post every month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2021, I didn't take up the challenge. I wrote just three posts in the entire year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the two years when I took the challenge, even though I wrote a few mediocre articles, I wrote a few good articles. In the other two years when I didn't take the challenge, my writing quality and quantity declined.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to this, I decided to take up the writing challenge again this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of limiting the 1,00,000 reward to my friend, I decided to extend it to all the readers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first person who calls out that there is no new blog post in a month will get the 1,00,000 reward. The next three people will get a small gift as a token of appreciation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will try my best to write at least one post every month. Let's wait till the end of the year and see how it goes.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>personal</category><category>writing</category><guid>http://avilpage.com/2022/01/resuming-writing-challenge.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 00:36:06 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>