<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Avil Page (Posts about faq)</title><link>http://avilpage.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://avilpage.com/tags/faq.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2018 14:36:18 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Some Frequently Asked Questions About This Blog</title><link>http://avilpage.com/2014/01/avil-page-frequently-asked-questions.html</link><dc:creator>Chillar Anand</dc:creator><description>&lt;div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"&gt;Q: What is Avilpage?&lt;br&gt;A: Just an e-page to write my personal stuff.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Q: Why there are no comments on this blog?&lt;br&gt;A: Comments are a good way of interacting and there are many benefits with that but they take a lot of time and I will loose the focus on the topics, so I disabled comments on my blog.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Q: No sharing buttons?&lt;br&gt;A: I just removed them and I don't want them here. If you really liked an article, send a message or a mail to your friends about that. That will be great.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Q: No Ads?&lt;br&gt;A: Unlike my previous blogs, I am not placing any ads here. I am getting a bad feeling about the ads and soon I will remove the ads from my previous blogs also.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Q: No Search?&lt;br&gt;A: Yeah no. Lets say you want to search about "movies". You can go to List of Avil Pages, press "Ctrl + F" and search for movies. If You need a better search go to Google and search "site:avilpage.com movies"&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Q: Why there is no subscribe button?&lt;br&gt;A: I don't want it to be there. I don't want a mail delivered to your inbox whenever I wrote some nonsense. When you have some free time, just check out here.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Q: I need to talk to you. How to contact you?&lt;br&gt;A: Ok, &lt;a href="http://www.avilpage.com/2014/01/avil-page-9-lets-talk.html"&gt;Lets Talk.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Q: Tech details of blog?&lt;br&gt;A: Domain registered with Godaddy and hosted on blogger platform. Using Simple Template.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>faq</category><guid>http://avilpage.com/2014/01/avil-page-frequently-asked-questions.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2014 11:47:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>