<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Avil Page (Posts about go)</title><link>http://www.avilpage.com</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://www.avilpage.com/tags/go.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2017 07:21:42 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Using Sourcegraph To Search Real Code!</title><link>http://www.avilpage.com/2014/09/using-sourcegraph-to-search-real-code.html</link><dc:creator>Chillar Anand</dc:creator><description>&lt;div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;What Is Sourcegraph Anyway?&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;i&gt;" Sourcegraph is a code search engine that lets you search across hundreds of thousands of libraries and browse code in the same way you can do in a great IDE. "&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.sourcegraph.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Sourcegraph&lt;/a&gt; is not the first code search engine ever built, neither it will be last, but it offers is completely different from all other code search engines like &lt;a href="http://nullege.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Nullege&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://code.ohloh.net/" target="_blank"&gt;OpenHUB&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;Why Should You Care?&lt;/h3&gt;I will explain a few situations where it makes developers life a little bit easier.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;1. Search Real Code:&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div&gt;Sourcegraph helps you to quickly search open source projects &amp;amp; see realcode examples. Let's say I am using &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="http://celeryproject.org/" target="_blank"&gt;Celery&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/b&gt;to schedule some tasks. I know there is &lt;b&gt;chord (&lt;/b&gt;a task that only executes after all of the tasks in a taskset has finished executing) but I don't know how to use it. I can use Sourcegraph to find &lt;b&gt;chord, &lt;/b&gt;look at its api, check out some real world examples. &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Here it doesn't sound Sourcegraph is much useful because you can go through the documentation and you can get all the information about it. But you won't find a lot of real world examples in documentation.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Also if you learning about a new module, it will take a while to wrap your head and get used to that module. What you can do is browse through sourcegraph to understand the api &amp;amp; immediately check out some real code where other programmers have used it for various purposes. I feel this helps a lot to start using a new module and get used to it quickly.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;2. Bad Documented Libraries:&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div&gt;There are tons of open source libraries &amp;amp; some of them have very good documentation. There are some good libraries which are documented badly or don't have documentation at all. It's a huge pain to to use a library with bad documentation. Here sourcegraph once again comes to rescue us by quickly navigating around the code. &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;3. Chrome Extension:&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div&gt;I spend significant time on Github browsing code. Sometimes I clone the repo and browse it on Emacs. But sometimes I just want to browse on Github itself. &lt;a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/sourcegraph/dgjhfomjieaadpoljlnidmbgkdffpack/details" target="_blank"&gt;Sourcegraph has chrome extension&lt;/a&gt; which lets you browse code quickly on GitHub by making every identifer a jump-to-definition link. By the way if you are a using it please write a review.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-qj0OXkUqFdo/VBx4g58SAHI/AAAAAAAAKz4/z923a766610/s1600/sourcegraph-review-usage.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"&gt;&lt;img border="0" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-qj0OXkUqFdo/VBx4g58SAHI/AAAAAAAAKz4/z923a766610/s1600/sourcegraph-review-usage.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;That's if for now. I came across Sourcegraph a couple of weeks back. From then on I am using it almost everyday. Currently it supports only Python, Go, Ruby, Node.js. I hope it will support for other languages soon. What I mentioned here is just a little introduction. Check out ProTips, &lt;a href="https://sourcegraph.com/help/doc" target="_blank"&gt;Sourcegraph docs&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a href="https://srclib.org/" target="_blank"&gt;srclib&lt;/a&gt;(a polyglot code analysis library, built with hackability in mind). If you are a Go programmer, read &lt;a href="https://leanpub.com/howdoiusesourcegraph" target="_blank"&gt;How do I use Sourcegraph with Go?&lt;/a&gt; (a short FREE ebook by Satish Talim).&lt;br&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br class="Apple-interchange-newline"&gt;========================================================================&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.avilpage.com/search/label/chrome%20extensions"&gt;More Chrome Extensions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>chrome extensions</category><category>go</category><category>sourcegraph</category><category>tech</category><guid>http://www.avilpage.com/2014/09/using-sourcegraph-to-search-real-code.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2014 13:23:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>