<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Avil Page (Posts about opinion)</title><link>http://avilpage.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://avilpage.com/tags/opinion.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 01:02:08 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Why Blog Posts Are Better Than Scientific Papers?</title><link>http://avilpage.com/2017/01/blog_posts_are_better_than_scientific_papers/</link><dc:creator>Chillar Anand</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Titus Brown wrote a blog post on why &lt;a href="http://ivory.idyll.org/blog/2017-top-ten-reasons-blog-posts.html"&gt;blog posts are better than scientific papers&lt;/a&gt;. Here are few more reasons for that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fast&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Publishing blog posts is lightning fast(how fast can you type?). You can just publish it with a click after writing. However with scientific papers you have to wait months to get your work published.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Mutability&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blog posts are easy to edit. If you are using a version controlled system like git, any one can easily collaborate. You can also leave comments on (most) blog posts and can have discussion with the author and/or others. Scientific papers once published are hard to change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;No Gatekeepers&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To publish blog posts, you can setup your own blog or use services like &lt;a href="http://medium.com"&gt;medium&lt;/a&gt;. There are no gatekeepers who says that you can't publish a blog post because they thinks its not worth it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Organic&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blog posts tend to be casual and organic. You can crack a joke and readers will enjoy it. Scientific papers are formal. You spray some sarcasm and your paper never gets published.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>blogging</category><category>opinion</category><guid>http://avilpage.com/2017/01/blog_posts_are_better_than_scientific_papers/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2017 17:03:38 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Why I Use CyanogenMod?</title><link>http://avilpage.com/2016/10/why-use-cyanogenmod.html</link><dc:creator>Chillar Anand</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;When listening to music, to switch tracks I want to use volume buttons. For this I have to use &lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.silentlexx.volbtntrackctrl&amp;amp;hl=en"&gt;Pocket Skip Track&lt;/a&gt; app.
CyanogenMod has inbuilt support for that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To interact with mobile from computer over wifi, &lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.ttxapps.wifiadb"&gt;wifi adb&lt;/a&gt; is required. CyanogenMod provides an option to enable this in &lt;code&gt;Developer Options&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To put mobile in recovery mode, &lt;a href="http://repo.xposed.info/module/com.ceco.kitkat.gravitybox"&gt;Gravity Box&lt;/a&gt; is required. This should be used only after installing Xposed framework. CyanogenMod has &lt;code&gt;Advanced reboot&lt;/code&gt; which provides option to put phone in recovery mode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Battery icon in status bar is very small. Having a text percentage indicator will be more useful. For this &lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=de.kroegerama.android4batpercent"&gt;battery percentage&lt;/a&gt; is required.
CyanogenMod has inbuilt circle/text indicators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Auto brighness stopped working after I have rooted Moto G4 plus. I had to use &lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.urbandroid.lux"&gt;twilight&lt;/a&gt; for auto brighness adjustment. With CyanogenMod, it is working fine. It also has a night mode option.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With stock android, auto rotate won't work in all directions. &lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.googlecode.eyesfree.setorientation"&gt;Set orientation&lt;/a&gt; app is required for that. CyanogenMod has inbuilt support for that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To adapt mobile display to the time of the day, flux app is required on stock android. CyanogenMod has inbuilt option for this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get superuser permissions, I have to root stock android. CyanogenMod comes with root permissions. To run &lt;code&gt;adb&lt;/code&gt; as root on stock android, &lt;code&gt;adbd insecure&lt;/code&gt; app is required. CyanogenMod works without it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stock android also doesn't provide any options to customize status bar. CyanogenMod has several options to customize it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are several other things where CyanogenMod excels when compared to stock android like themes, privacy guard e.t.c. However, CyanogenMod comes with a lot of inbuilt features(batteries included) and that is the main reason for me to use it.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>android</category><category>opinion</category><guid>http://avilpage.com/2016/10/why-use-cyanogenmod.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2016 14:05:09 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>