<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Avil Page (Posts about personal)</title><link>http://avilpage.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://avilpage.com/tags/personal.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 03:57:36 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>On Resuming Writing Challenge</title><link>http://avilpage.com/2022/01/resuming-writing-challenge.html</link><dc:creator>Chillar Anand</dc:creator><description>&lt;p align="center"&gt;
&lt;img height="300" width="800" src="http://avilpage.com/images/writing_challenge.jpg"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align="center"&gt;
Photo by Kaboompics on Pexels
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2018, I decided to write at least one blog post per month throughout the year. Even though I tried to write posts every month, I couldn't publish anything in few months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2019, I went a step ahead and made a legal(?) agreement with a friend. I paid him 1,00,000 rupees and told him that he could keep the money as a reward if I failed to write a blog post every month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This agreement kept me on my toes. I didn't miss writing a single month in 2019. I stayed awake on the last days of the month to finish and publish the post before midnight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2020, I took up the challenge again and I was able to write at least one post every month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2021, I didn't take up the challenge. I wrote just three posts in the entire year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the two years when I took the challenge, even though I wrote a few mediocre articles, I wrote a few good articles. In the other two years when I didn't take the challenge, my writing quality and quantity declined.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to this, I decided to take up the writing challenge again this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of limiting the 1,00,000 reward to my friend, I decided to extend it to all the readers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first person who calls out that there is no new blog post in a month will get the 1,00,000 reward. The next three people will get a small gift as a token of appreciation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will try my best to write at least one post every month. Let's wait till the end of the year and see how it goes.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>personal</category><category>writing</category><guid>http://avilpage.com/2022/01/resuming-writing-challenge.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 00:36:06 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>