<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Avil Page (Posts about pycharm)</title><link>http://avilpage.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://avilpage.com/tags/pycharm.xml" type="application/rss+xml" rel="self"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2020 01:25:50 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Essential PyCharm (Intellij) Plugins To Improve Productivity</title><link>http://avilpage.com/2019/03/intellij-pycharm-plugins-productivity.html</link><dc:creator>Chillar Anand</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;As per 2019 &lt;a href="https://www.jetbrains.com/research/python-developers-survey-2018/#development-tools"&gt;JetBrains survery&lt;/a&gt;, PyCharm is the most widely used(36%) IDE for Python development. Eventhough PyCharm comes with lot of built in features, there are a lot of plugins available for PyCharm and other Intellij IDEs. In this article, we will see some plugins which will boost our productivity during development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Highlight Bracket Pair&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of manually scanning where a bracket starts/ends, &lt;a href="https://plugins.jetbrains.com/plugin/10465-highlightbracketpair"&gt;Highlight Bracket Pair&lt;/a&gt; will automatically hightlight the bracket pairs based on cursor position.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Rainbow Brackets&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Highlight Bracket Pair will hightlight the bracket pair around the cursor. When there are multiple bracket pairs deeply nested, &lt;a href="https://plugins.jetbrains.com/plugin/10080-rainbow-brackets"&gt;Rainbow Brackets&lt;/a&gt; will highlight matching bracket pairs with matching rainbow colors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Grep Console&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When running a django/flask server or any Python script which generates lot of output, it is hard to filter out required output on console. &lt;a href="https://plugins.jetbrains.com/plugin/7125-grep-console"&gt;Grep Console&lt;/a&gt; can filter or highlight output based on specific conditions which makes it easier to debug the code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Save Actions&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of manually optimizing imports or reformating code when changes are made, we can use &lt;a href="https://plugins.jetbrains.com/plugin/7642-save-actions"&gt;Save Actions&lt;/a&gt; which will automatically run a set of actions on every file save.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Key Promoter&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are new to PyCharm or an experienced user who is using mouse instead of key board shortcuts, &lt;a href="https://plugins.jetbrains.com/plugin/9792-key-promoter-x"&gt;Key Promoter&lt;/a&gt; will show relevant key board shortcut when mouse is used inside IDE. This provides an easy way to learn keyboard shortcuts faster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;String Manipulation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To convert lower case letters to upper case letter, &lt;a href="https://plugins.jetbrains.com/plugin/2162-string-manipulation"&gt;String manipulation plugin&lt;/a&gt; will be useful. In addition to lower/upper case conversion, it also provides options to convert to cameCase, kebab-case, PascalCase etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Ace Jump&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To move caret to a particular position in the editor without mouse,
&lt;a href="https://plugins.jetbrains.com/plugin/7086-acejump"&gt;AceJump plugin&lt;/a&gt; will be useful. It allows to quickly navigate the caret to any position in the editor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are some plugins which will boost developers productivity while writing and debugging code in PyCharm or other JetBrains IDE.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>django</category><category>pycharm</category><category>python</category><guid>http://avilpage.com/2019/03/intellij-pycharm-plugins-productivity.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2019 15:51:21 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>